▍2026 美网 女单第三轮
郑钦文 1-6 7-6³ 7-5 凯斯 · 赛后场上采访
has watched something absolutely
美网这里刚刚上演了
remarkable here at the US Open.
完全不可思议的一幕
You're going to have to help us understand
你得帮我们理解一下这场
this one because you were five love down
因为决胜盘你 0-5 落后
in the deciding set yet we stand here
而现在我们站在这里
on the back of a 7-5 victory
是因为你 7-5 拿下了
in the deciding set.
那个决胜盘
How did that just happen?
这到底是怎么发生的？
Remarkable story.
太不可思议了
Well, first of all, I have to say Madison Keys,
首先我得说 凯斯
she play amazing in that moment.
她那个时候打得非常好
I don't feel like she made 5-0
我不觉得她能 5-0 领先
because I play so bad.
是因为我打得太差
I think she play amazing.
我觉得是她打得好
And after I just telling myself,
后来我就一直告诉自己
keep holding every single point.
每一分都要咬住
Never give up.
永远别放弃
Stay there.
就留在场上
And somehow little by little it just
然后不知怎么 一点一点
happened.
它就真的发生了
I mean, finally one time a bit luck
终于有那么一次
is on my side.
运气站在我这边
I'm so happy. And I know
我太开心了 我知道
in the last match she also did that turn back
她上一场也完成过逆转
and it's not bad I did that once as well
我这次也做到一次 挺好
but honestly also this is first time happen
但老实说 这是第一次
in my career I turn up like 0-5 usually
生涯里从 0-5 追回来
before it's always 1-5, 2-5
以前最多是 1-5 或 2-5
but yeah it was very dramatic match for me
这场球对我来说太跌宕
but we both show up really strong tennis
但我们都打出了很强的球
and I want to say thank you
我想说声谢谢
for the crowd who come
谢谢今天来现场的观众
to supporting us today doesn't matter
来给我们加油 不管
if it's supporting Maddie or me I mean,
你支持的是麦迪还是我
thank you very much.
真的非常感谢
This is truly one
这真的是
of the loudest atmospheres we've had here
我们见过气氛最热的一场
on Grandstand at this year's US Open.
今年美网 Grandstand 球场
You posted
你前几天
on your social media the other day
在社交媒体上发过一句
that you said fortune favors the brave.
天佑勇者
I feel like that very much was the story
我觉得这正是
of that match.
这场球的写照
As that final set began progressing
决胜盘一点点往下走
and you started working your way back
你开始一点点追回来
in, did your belief just continue growing
你的信念是不是
and growing?
越来越强？
Well, yes.
是的
I I always believe you know especially
我一直相信 尤其是
I think when I was down four five it
我 4-5 落后的时候
was very tough game and in that moment I
那一局非常难 那一刻
show no emotion cuz I know was never end
我没有表现出任何情绪
of match I just keep fighting keep
因为我知道比赛还没完
going there I mean yes I think brave
我就一直拼 一直往前
is the word today cuz
勇敢就是今天的关键词
against Maddie you can't be too passive
对麦迪你不能太被动
if not she will kill you and I think I find
否则她会碾压你
the right balance at the end
我觉得最后我找到了
of the game well I'm just super happy
那个平衡 我特别开心
to this match it's like Yeah.
这场球 就是 是啊
Wow. What I can say.
哇 我还能说什么呢
Wow. Yeah.
哇 是啊
Qinwen, just if you wouldn't mind,
钦文 如果你不介意
reflect a little bit on the journey you've
聊聊你这一路走来
had since the last time you played
从你上一次打美网
at the US Open in 2024.
那是 2024 年
Obviously, injury issues with your elbow.
后来是你的肘伤
You went away, you had surgery,
你离开赛场 做了手术
and you are fighting back.
现在一路打回来
And you are fighting, it feels,
而且看得出来 你打球时
with a real fire in your belly,
心里像有一团火
especially on the back of a performance like
尤其是刚打完
that.
这样一场之后
Would you feel like you're close
你觉得自己是不是
to being back to your best now?
已经接近最好的状态了？
because it certainly looks like it, doesn't it,
因为看起来真的很像
folks?
对吧各位？
Wow. Yes.
哇 是的
I mean, I just enjoy so much to play here.
我真的很享受在这里打球
It's like I enjoying to fight here every day.
我享受每天在这里拼
And after the surgery was not easy.
手术之后并不容易
Feels like I lost a bit my energy
感觉我丢了一些能量
on the tennis court.
在球场上
And I've been through really tough
这三四五个月
this three, four, five months.
我过得非常难
I think that's the worst period of my time
我觉得那是最糟的一段
in my career since I entered to the pro.
转职业以来最糟的
But luckily thanks to my team,
幸好 谢谢我的团队
we've been working really hard
我们一直在很努力地练
at the IMG Academy after Toronto.
多伦多之后在 IMG 学院
And yeah,
是啊
the hard work pays off finally a bit.
努力终于有了一点回报
I mean, I want to say thanks
我想先说声谢谢
to my team first brings me here.
谢谢团队带我走到这儿
Let's keep going.
我们继续往前走
I mean, I never give up during the match.
比赛里我从没放弃过
I think that's the positive things right now.
我觉得这是最积极的一点
Well, listen, through qualifiers now
从资格赛一路打上来
through to the second week
现在进了美网
of the US Open.
第二周
Give it up for Qinwen Zheng.
为郑钦文鼓掌